scientists find themselves at the center
of a major controversy after
successfully reanimating the brain
removed from the skull of the deceased
this is man-made Horrors Beyond
Comprehension scientists wanted to see
if they could reanimate a brain hours
after death and they used the brains of
slaughtered pigs they flooded it with
cryoprotectives and neuroprotectants and
restored circulation four hours later
using a device similar to ECMO which
provides external oxygenated blood
similar to what the heart would do the
controversy comes from a philosophical
question brain in a bat because they
were able to restore neural activity and
brain waves which are considered the
difference between a brain dead patient
and the patient who may wake up the idea
is whether or not it's ethical to keep a
brain alive in a vat although under
these circumstances they did not have
external stimuli unlike our brain
organized they do not believe that
they're living in the literal Matrix
aside from the ethical concerns of
keeping one of these adorable
intelligent little animals brains alive
in
object horror we may be able to restore
life to one's brain a lot longer than we
thought was probable this also comes at
the heels of other discoveries where
electrocution of the brain also known as
deep current stimulation has been able
to temporarily restore some degree of
Consciousness in previously thought
brain dead patients though our entire
view of medicine may be changing in the
near future